just went live excited see you ready to
light an clock but they were so three
minutes late so yeah yeah no that was
the right choice
I feel like basically redoing what we
did yesterday which is giving you an
update on our projects and then say
anything that we want to get help with
from that Sam said he couldn't make it
today I'm sure you guys saw okay I was
confused I would thought he was just
saying it to me and then I saw your
faces that he had made a messenger like
all of us in it and then I sent this to
Shiloh as well but like 45 minutes ago
so I don't know if she's coming either
but I think just being here showing up
doing it and then showcasing hopefully
more people Cobb and then I'm gonna do
it right now remind me at the end
because I only rewatch the ends of these
to post the link for both our Friday
session and our Saturday session today
or tomorrow so that there's much more
time for people to schedule yes I want
to be part of that this is this is what
it looks like and so maybe we can also
craft a bit of what this does look like
just didn't party in which I'm never the
best at for Brittany what is it we're
doing during this hour that isn't me
rambling about it for three paragraphs
right get together I'm gonna talk about
this let me do that we don't need that
so but you can read me what we did
yesterday how is recent score going I'll
pick Bentley
good so kind of reiterate and then talk
about some new stuff in the last 24
hours
sorry
yeah so I've I was able to work 30 hours
this last week which is really good on
reason score of about I'm about to
update the demo on the website with the
new system which will allow me to throw
out features a lot quicker I posted on
Twitter under my my character name gully
bot no one has responded to that idea
but I can still gather data without that
and the
later I'll come in and say a goalie bot
has an opinion and that's when people
will stop all over him because it's all
it's only when you have opinions on
Twitter that people stop you but they
don't that'll be the engagement says oh
I believe this and then I'll take the
data and just repeat rinse and repeat
and then today I'm also since it deals
with debating stuff I'm in a group
called the canal debate lab and we had
to or the people join who have two other
projects so there will be some progress
and in that area as people get to know
and argue about arguing which is always
fun that's so that's that's kind of
progress and I guess if we're gonna do
full accountability which we haven't
said we're gonna do or not then if you
you know sometimes you would also say
what you're going to do next week so
next week I will be or between now and
the next meeting I will be releasing the
new demo code and I hopefully will be
starting to generate some content and
agile if you have any topics that you
think might be debatable or that you'd
like to see a structure debate on if
you'd let me know and I'll see if those
would fit into my initial set of
experiments just yeah I mean my for wiki
election I'm kind of taking the opposite
others you know think you're sort of
starting it like a simpler topic which
makes sense I understand why you're
doing that because I'm sort of trying to
get like just a barrage of evidence I'm
starting at like the top or I'm trying
to climate change in vaccines so yeah I
mean yeah I'm not sure if you're ready
to tackle those kind of topics yet but I
do want to stay smaller but if you run
across the one that you don't want to
tackle but you think would be nice then
okay know one of the ones that I might
tackle to start with just to sort of
keep it more light is flutter I'm not
sure if that's
wait is this is the what again flutter
or I guess flat the shape of being yeah
yes I have been thinking about that one
the other two have a debate yeah did
heavy did you see the documentary that
came out a year or two ago with the they
actually had someone flatter two-thirds
participate in the documentary I didn't
the documentary I saw some people review
the documentary okay it was really
fascinating and they did a really good
job of being respectful of people you
would ordinarily dismiss so that's why I
thought it was good
is there anything you need help with
Bentley that's a good question I don't
know if anyone does have any opinion so
the topic that I chose was just the
ketogenic way of eating or the keto diet
so if anyone has any like when they hear
that what are the concerns that that you
have like oh you know you're gonna die
of a heart attack or stuff like that
it'd be good to get a feeling for like
your top three or four reasons why you
might be scared if you heard a family
member was going to do that or something
like that or you know if you're a
die-hard Quito person like I am then why
you think it works but yeah any topics
on a and just to go on Twitter and look
up gully bots and I can give you a link
and and post there so that everyone can
see it if you if you want to be private
you can always message it to me and I'll
use the data though cool so yeah another
topic which type information I'm not
sure accessible it is is I mean either
go broad and go breathe Pacific
legislation or just we simply talk about
pit bulls and sort of the the
controversy there there's yeah that's an
interesting one because you could just
do you know our certain dog breeds more
aggressive than others where people deny
or there's the nuance of saying a whole
breed could be but that doesn't
necessarily apply to a specific dog
right
then but I think for my system a a
specific piece of legislation that's
would be ideal right okay because it
gets more specific otherwise right cool
interesting so on just on a topic I'm
talking about too long I think a couple
of cities have recently started to
repeal them because they've gone back
interviewed and said this didn't
actually lower the number of dog bites
or dog attacks why are we having this
legislation then that's why we get and
it's not working um I think Denver is
either has done it or like it's close to
I'm doing it okay yeah that sounds like
a good topic Thanks is that something
that honestly I'll probably keep away
from election cuz it's a bit too close
to me so I don't think that I could be
impartial yeah sorry to when people want
dogs to put down or been open and even
if you don't have one that's potentially
part of it um so Adriel do you want to
do with election or shadow you can do
what i won't remember the name of your
project animal come on the project just
I posed a about that I guess my project
future project with the having an art
show that kind of introduces these
different ideas so it's in the making
I'm making a lot of art but I also want
to introduce these alternative ways of
society to function with all these great
solutions so I guess it's just on the
backburner a TRO they want me to go
where do you want to go um I'm no sure
one sec let me meet my phone because
it's beeping at me for some reason
there we go so wiki election this last
week it's been good
I've been working on the presentation
for the news topic I had wiki elections
split into four topics as I went to work
on the fourth topic news I found out
it's really just the same as the first
one which is sort of the core feature
because the news feature sort of comes
out of those so really this next session
that I'm gonna be doing in just under
three hours is kind of looping back and
doing the first session again but this
time with a spin on news and it's
actually the first time I'll be covering
a couple of the sort of specific topics
that have a few new graphics to show off
is the right word but throw it into the
ether of the Internet and see what
happens I guess that's not what
connection the step for this week will
be to continue working on the
presentation just to keep it moving but
then specifically I really want to get
the specs done and up so that I can get
them on up work I weird sort of blip is
that my credit card is expiring this
month so now up work is winding at me
that my credit card is expiring and may
have issues allowing me to start one so
I have to wait for that to come in the
mail for the new one which is not
something I expected to hold it up but
what well whatever that is it being fine
I think that's about it for now and
quick tip if you want to try it
oftentimes you can just figure out what
the next date would be and put it in yet
and it all work I know that because some
startups have started automatically
rolling your dates that's actually a
feature that some of those will talk to
the banking company and there's
something in a lot of the terms on the
credit card that said just go it if a
company is paying for this service
because they sometimes it's not even the
same card number they just get like your
new card number and expiry and all that
information if they had the previous one
and they're paying for a certain service
but yeah anything you want help with
during the during the hour um I mean I'm
I am looking for anyone that wants to
sort of attend as another talking head
in the election sessions because you
know if it's not that it's just me
talking and that's not as interesting
I've done like really five or six
sessions now and the best one by far was
the one where Edward cake came in and it
was the topic on science and we talked
about that and it was great it was well
longer than normal but we covered a lot
of good stuff so what's your next topic
because you are doing them kind of by
topic right yeah so now so basically
starting today I'm doing news and then
I'm gonna cycle through the same three
topics sort of you know to covering one
every two weeks so it's news politics
and science and it's sort of the
umbrella features around those and
whenever did it we kind of ended up
talking about the whole thing because he
didn't know that much about it but we
sort of used sought the like discussion
of science as the entry point and that
was actually quite good because he's a
scientist has that background and he was
able to come at it from that way and
when are you doing him again so I I do
them on Saturdays at noon pacific and so
i'm doing one today and then i'll do one
in two weeks in two weeks in two weeks
okay yeah i've been i've been thinking
of joining you on one of those okay yeah
sometime sounds good there's a certain
topic of those three that like speaks to
you more i be nice so yeah either yeah i
guess either the politics or the science
maybe the science but politics or
science the news one i'm a little less i
think we need to judge the news but yeah
i guess i can't really talk to them all
but yeah yeah i mean it ends up being
the same conversation sort of in the end
cuz it's all about the underlying
evidence and what it supports on the top
end but it's yeah kind of get in and i
would want you to get I don't seemed
like you do have some content I don't
know if that's in case no one joins you
or if you do have a set of features that
you want to go through over the next
several months that sort of how I'm
arranging it is each of those three
topics is to cover the features for that
area I was splitting them out like
really sort of modular like talking to a
developer style and then as I was
talking about it I'm like this just
doesn't resonate with people I think
like it's too it's too technical so I
started to loop it into like the really
high level modules and sort of what kind
of area of information these features
should hopefully fix there is some
overlap between them which is where it
gets a little bit murky but that's fine
cool so I can update you on what I've
done in the last week
besides the breakdown yeah that was just
exactly what was needed at the time but
I stopped I decided to not go live at
6:00 p.m. every night I why I ever
thought that would work I don't know
now I'm going live at 8:30 in the
morning every day and today I did a
20-minute session because I totally
forgot it nine o'clock is not an hour
after 8:30 and I've had written Rick
Nick joined a few a few of them which
has been awesome for a little bit event
today I had someone who I don't know how
long he's been a subscriber to the
channel or if he even was before but he
came he came on which was always a
little dicey you never know what what
you're gonna get but he was that he
seemed to be a someone from from Ireland
who who is interested in doing what I'm
gonna be doing this next week was I'm
gonna reach out to Kiera because she
said that she was interested in doing a
solution raising on mental health
emotional health
ensuring dream Kovach 19 especially and
so I would love snood solution raising
on that and if she's willing to do it
live jury in that hour that would be
ideal because then people can showcase
what that what that looks like it also
means it's a little bit because
assertion ratings are on this website
this YouTube channel and then my live
broadcasts every hour on on the Jubilee
saves the world Channel
so it's it's different like it's ill but
the point is is to just focus on
something for those hours and to see now
can we have more of the meta
conversation so possibly try it at least
one of those throughout the seven days
to be a live solution raising and so
that one the first one will be on on
mental health and what I would love help
with if somebody has a solution in some
I guess just how to to grow the audience
and what a toll and I talked to a
yesterday after our our board meeting of
like um what does this look like it's
it's different it's like a process
raising as opposed to a solution a
solution or a saying is like the
conversation we're having but what I'm
really looking for is a group of people
who want to focus on the conversation
about a conversation that I've been
wanting
that's right like what is the process
look like how can we create it from the
ground up of what would it look like to
create something with 10,000 people even
though of course the actual core group
of people who are creating it or 5 to 10
people how do we create something with a
hundred people in zoom and then with a
hundred people and zoom how to create
something for a thousand people and then
for a thousand people how do we how does
everyone invite ten people and this
process will still work and so working
through that is going to be messy and
we're gonna try new things and someone
who's who's comfortable doing the
solution racing's itself don't need to
be live on camera they can be on zoom we
can be doing it in a way that people are
more comfortable but the meta
conversation of the process raisi and of
like what does this look like we're
creating it for humanity how do we get
ten thousand people involved I think
that one does need to be live recorded
for everyone so that is what I would
love is help on how do I find those
people or do I just keep doing it I'm
doing and any thoughts any thoughts on
that I need feedback on that so we're
done with the beginning part of this
this where we update everyone I don't
know what I'm taking on for next week
besides what I said covered it so one
small thing because it's not really my
project but there's something to work on
I have a prototype for like that
together Tech game B project sort of
like a group portal I sent the login
over to jewbilee I think she briefly was
able to log in and check it out and I
guess now that word that stuff I can
probably send it over to you Bentley if
you want to try and and register and I
can make you own your project I took the
projects from that spreadsheet and
imported them only a couple are sort of
visible on the public side cuz once it's
done testing I wanna be able to contact
those people and say do you want it live
but it's meant to be sort of like a hey
anybody can go there and see what
projects are listed what the projects
need help with and want sort of events
people are planning and then if you log
in you can sign up for events and you
know submit a project and ask the help
for the project and that kind of thing
so I'm probably you don't send it out to
you you Bentley and then at some point
if other people that have projects or
that want to help
we're projects are interested in trying
it out we can start sort of a it's a
closed beta or probably closed alpha is
a better thing because it's still pretty
early yes yeah that sounds good so that
would normally the process that we kind
of talked about for these meetings was
called the hot seat version of a
mastermind which normally then you know
we do that little round at the beginning
or people talk about what they're going
what they've done since the last meeting
what they're gonna do for the next
meeting if they want and you know any
any things that they could use help on
and then usually it's the way that
process was you choose someone that
would then that we've been focusing on
their specific needs and of course if
you have time you know it could be more
than one person I don't think we chose
who would be this week powerful thing
for their project a bit I already got a
little feedback and I gave Adria little
feedback so I don't know Ghibli a few
before we want to focus on I'm done with
that I also think that possibly Shiloh
if you want help with like more concrete
like what your project is write a name
for it something like that so I want to
leave it up to Shiloh whether she
whether that it's something you want to
be in the hot seat or whether you want
to not be long um I think I think I'll
wait I'm still just kind of like I've
been thinking about this for a long time
but I don't know exactly what I'm asking
for yet or so I'll probably just wait I
am um I'm still trying to figure out all
the different things even just how to
get here today I had those like I've
received a message on my phone but then
I had to turn around and realize oh I
need to email it to myself it's just so
silly I'm like totally behind on the
tech and I'm not sure I'll ever catch up
so but I am interested on all these
things I listen to part of yesterday's
video on when you were talking about
the keto diet and Bentley is that part
of your project like yeah so well my
part is to debate have effective debates
on controversial topics and so that's
kind of a small one that I chose for my
first topic but so the the project isn't
actually aligned with that that's just
our topic and then I might do pit bulls
next like that trail suggesting but do
you have a place where I can go and like
listen to your conversation about it or
is it just text it's gonna be on text
base and right now I just there's not a
location yet so all right now I just
kind of posted the question on Twitter
and then I'm gonna take when people give
and then I'm gonna put it into the
system so right now it's not it's not
gonna be mature enough that people can
actually just go on and start entering
data so my thought is I'll collect the
data then I'll throw it back out to
Twitter and collect the data in and
Facebook so yeah I'll have a link
hopefully in a week or so where it has
kind of the first things that goalie
bought which is the character has
learned so yeah that's that's the plan
and goalie bot is the name of your life
yeah so that's kind of the moderator the
character that will be taking watching
everyone's conversations it's a it's a
it's kind of a moderator on a
conversation that that has no
preconceived notions and the technology
itself underlying it I've called reasons
score but now I'm starting to realize
that a numerical score confuses people
and so maybe goalie bought would be
better so those are the two things that
the technology and then kind of the
character of it quite so I'm trying out
several things to see what works I don't
I don't really know what's going to hit
yet yeah so yeah I'd appreciate either
if you want to give feedback on
on Twitter so that people see it you
know and I could do like no yeah what do
Twitter it's just like human me I'm like
okay I'm not going to go there via
Facebook I'm so limited like okay hardly
at all
I know yeah I'm thinking at some point
in the future when it gets a little bit
more mature I will have videos and kind
of like we're discussing yesterday a
very ungainly like thing whereas there's
actually a game show type of using the
tech although technically I just I just
remembered in the game show thing you
get points for getting for putting in
good information regardless of which
side it's on so technically it's more
collaborative and just having it be a
game show and debate is just to get all
the people that are used to game a to
watch it but it is kind of pushed
towards the game be space anyway so yeah
at some point in the future I hope to
have some kind of content and and I just
talked to my brother this morning about
maybe he and I should come up with a
topic to debate but whoever does it it
would be really really slow cuz it's
like let's decide on a point and type it
in so I'd have to kind of edit the video
down to be less boring so he owes me a
favor so he might do that with that with
gully bot like if I respond to to it on
Twitter do I need to pro and con
separately gonna be like you know you
know it's not sustainable for everyone
on the planet to do it but it helps with
individual's health you absolutely need
it right that's gonna be like you don't
need to it's I mean it's right now it's
just manual we're all gonna be taking it
in and putting it in it's just a
communication device outside of the
system I built take to have the
conversation where people are interested
so yeah so however you want to I think
it would be interesting to see in a
pro/con format dalvik yeah I see so it's
still in like The Wizard of Oz prototype
style where there's still the man behind
the curtain it's just ya helper yeah and
there's a good chance that it will
always be moderate well so this first
phase is a highly moderated one so
everything will kind of go through me so
the goal isn't really to have a debate
system it but it is to have a resource
that has everyone's concerns in an
organized format right the first thing
so it's really gonna be like a a fact
check website with a lot of more input
from other people but still not direct
input yet because when you were talking
about kaliba remember when I saw it I
was confused about how it was recent
score and I was like I don't understand
how this is a heading because if reason
score and I didn't know how to interact
with it so I didn't know and other
people that might be something the
reason it's not getting feedback is like
one people don't know what it is even
though it's a kilo robot and so having
more people participate with that right
of like here's how you actually
participate so it was like I don't know
it says weird spot between I'm like now
that I know you're just collecting and
I'm like I don't have to do anything
specific that it's not some kind of like
algorithm that is smart and it's gonna
you know like I have to talk to it like
it's those freaking annoying robots that
respond to you on people's websites that
are like give me your email address yeah
I really should respond to it with some
of the stuff that I think I'm the topic
and just as so people can see some
interaction yeah yeah I just kind of
threw it out there I don't really expect
people to interact with it I really
think it's gonna be more when I guys do
I'm gonna do it today I learned that
oh that Kido is perfect for everybody
and then see what everyone says a bit of
conversation date yeah yeah nice which
is easy to do on Twitter oh yeah it's
harder to not do I do
right
I guess I have another quick question
I'm wondering so Bentley you're a
developer and Adriel are you also a
developer I'm not a developer I work
with developers but I'm not a developer
myself okay and my question is is
Bentley are you doing any developing
with hollow chamber no wait I'm sorry
developing in what Halloween Hollow
all the way I don't know gene Oh on the
hollow chain stuff yeah
no but I'm open to using that as the
base database technology for any of the
tools I want that I'm building another
kind of database system similar to that
is gun so that that is one of the
options that's using a hollow chain
although my preference would actually be
hash graph which is yeah we could get
into the debate on reason why to use one
or not but but yeah some sort of
blockchain technology I'm useful maybe
I'm a little bit is when I think of
hollow chain I think of it as like it
seems to be easier mapping data and it's
connections where is blockchain is more
like a centralized I know it's
decentralized in a way but it's also
kind of one central ledger is that right
what it was to be centralized controller
register
I thought hollow chain was I know I read
it it's been a while since I've looked
at it oh yeah yeah control your identity
yeah yeah and so hollow chain kind of
helps is that's similar to the gun
database where you kind of have your own
collection of the data yeah
yeah so I haven't used it specifically
but it's on my list of technologies to
consider
right now I'm using more traditional
database but I'm creating the system to
where you can easily move it on to any
sort of back-end well let me know if you
do any research on it and I do have some
ideas about the thing that we're trying
to create that ghost that uses that type
just because it has a different type of
tracking mechanism I guess you'd say and
everybody can have their own yet I
believe we can mark to deposit it right
anyway it's probably really out there
another time yeah yeah and definitely if
you want to have a chat about it we
could always schedule meeting and yeah
right I can take the hot seat
everywhere I hope that so umm I said
what I would what I most want is well
there's two things one of which is to
figure out kind of what that hour in the
morning looks like although I'm a kind
of okay with letting it evolve and and
try new things and see what's just about
really just being in the seat on camera
for an hour and see how that evolves and
and growing an audience both for my
channel but also for just projects in
general but what I would love is for
that hour to actually be have it leads
somewhere have it be something that is
kind of like a solution or easy like I
said doing live solution radians but
what I would having a group of people
who are focused on how can we create the
process for solution raising so that is
it solution raising is a specific type
of conversation that gets the spark of
the idea from the group it's pretty easy
to extrapolate that into a hundred
people on zoom' but it's but then we
just have the spark of an idea I want
people who want to have a conversation
on how do we actually get 10,000 people
how do we get a process with a thousand
people how do we what what and have that
conversation live on cameras of other
people who don't want to be on camera
can contribute to yes I would want to be
one of the 10,000 but I don't want to be
one of the people on camera like to get
a better understanding and so that was a
lot of things I realized but
pie-in-the-sky would really love to have
four to five other people to meet with I
realize every day for people right now
8:30 to 9:30 would be a lot so having
that stay kind of like the journey
Occupy movement when they had two
meetings a day you didn't really need to
attend them because they reiterated what
was happening in the last one have it be
something that people don't need to show
up for consistently and it's those
things are diabolically opposed just
like to have people just show up and do
a project raising and they can show up
and do money for that day they don't
need to have a movie for it so possibly
even just picking one day a week that is
focused on the more meta this is what
this is kind of like what we're doing
with together tech on Fridays but doing
it for project raising and happy people
who want to participate once a week but
you know 8:30 to have the more Matt the
conversation so ideas thoughts clarity I
mean kind of a small simple one for the
like being able to you know or being
able to miss them and not having to
attend every one I kind of had the same
issue with the last reams for kwikki
election and one of the things that I
might end up doing is having sort of
like a templated like here's the you
know spiel that I do in the first two
minutes or five minutes or whatever that
is and then after it's posted on YouTube
you can go in there and add a comment
and saying look if you want to skip the
spiel click here because most people are
going to be watching it either not live
so if you're not attending in the first
two or five minutes you'll miss it which
I guess in this case is probably a good
thing and then if you're watching it
live and you've watched you know three
in a row and you're like I get it you
can click to skip it and you just go
into the meat and potatoes of the actual
conversation I can ask you more is it
just a link in the description it says
start at three minutes and then it
starts at three minutes or is there an
actually an option to skip ahead I think
the easiest thing would probably be in
the description I haven't played with
adding like the YouTube tiles that
you'll see in videos I'm not sure if you
can do those on unlike recorded live
videos my guess is you probably can yeah
I think you can and then edit any live
video and make it right last my slide
right yeah so I'm assuming that all the
same features are available yeah you
could use that like the hotel
but click you're good I believe you can
use that to skip two parts in the same
video but worst case yeah you can just
use the the timestamp links in the
description and then sort of say hey
we're gonna do the spiel if you want to
click it you know there's a link in the
description to skip to that part I think
that works for both like people who come
into the stream and are like what's
going on what are we chatting about
there could be like go watch any of the
previous ones and watch the first two to
three minutes five minutes and then
people who are constantly just watching
the replay because it gets people time
to be part of it so most people don't
show up in the first two to five minutes
so yeah no I like that and honestly I
don't have one I don't know how much you
got like I'm here what are we talking
about and so having it more focused on
solution raising which and yeah figuring
out us feel giving it every day for two
to five minutes and then also having
that possibility people can skip it if
they're not watching it live as well as
can re-watch it if they come in right
and depending how complex it gets you
might almost have like two parts you
might have like just a really generic
here's what we're doing and that's like
a minute I think they got two minute
here's what we did in the last session
or last few sessions and then be like
you can skip to whatever you want here's
the timestamps do without what you will
yeah yeah I can reiterate probably what
was like my own agenda before we talked
about I mean ideally I would also like
something to have that role possibly
someone who doesn't want to be on camera
who wants to show up and do that even if
they're just doing out on Mondays we're
just you know on tuesdays to be the
person who takes notes and says yes this
is what we discussed cuz that's not my
strong suit he's like he doesn't seem
like rewatching it don't sell me an hour
which I would never do but anyway so
having someone who could possibly take
on that role and having a portion of
this that's not like what is needed
again I would love to have a
concentrated group of people who are
meeting like on camera to have this
conversation what day of the week works
but also not role of note-taker for
every single day and have someone take
the notes and then I can update the
description would be it's amazing how
many of these like types of sessions
that person would be great for yes
absolutely
you're also one for this would be great
and for our Friday meetings and for
of it but like luckily their lives so II
like you could rewatch them and get the
gist at least they're like transparently
there they're just not transparently
like they're not accessible they're not
usable their current format as easily as
having here's what we discussed in
here's what was decided I don't think
there's a free version but in the
business world there's apps where it's
like you can sign up for kind of like a
paid bot where can join your zoom room
and it records it and it transcribes it
so it says like okay Jubilee saying this
at this point in time because it knows
that you're talking and then you know if
Bentley unmutes and talks it says oh now
Bentley's talking so in the actual
transcript it says Jubilee Bo diddly
blah blah blah and then it's not always
perfect but it helps sort of set the
table for know he didn't say that that's
in speech to text issues I'll just you
know correct yeah but it might be a good
start the next level and then it's not
work for like it's like that what's
actually important about what was right
but it is a good focus to have transfer
there are ways to do a video transcript
like
honor dot IO but it's a paid service
there's people in the game space and
have it who like it just does that it
transcribes and generally tries to
figure out with your voice person one
person two and I think you can then tell
them person 1 into R so it says you know
oh sorry I think I have seen YouTube
doing text I have seen YouTube doing
text-to-speech
I think yet they have like you can tell
it to run the like suggested closed
captioning and it scans it and it's
fairly accurate it's got some pretty
comical issues sometimes but you can go
in there and edit them you see that was
live video can you do gif closed caption
online video I think there is a feature
I think of it might just be like if you
put it on a delay or maybe it's just the
recordings I've seen is I'm pretty sure
you probably could have it run on a
recorded video but I think I've heard
you can do it on live I would try to I
would be interested but yeah what so
creating this feel it's two to five
minutes and then wreak happy what we did
in the last session and then giving my
my ask about
what I would like and then I can shoot
the for the next one okay here's
how you can join here's how this is
going I mean I can probably figure out
that spiel in less than five minutes
even if I am on tangents whichever one's
the better one I can cut out and use is
the go to this and listen to this if you
if you want to know what we are talking
about and what is what is going on and
where we currently currently are like
right now it will just be in the
description of the previous one and the
previous one and there isn't necessarily
someone to go to house here's what we've
talked about in last 20 which is just
its own document and copy and pasting
but it's not a ton website nor do I want
it to be at the moment like it's just
what is capable I can do a description
especially if someone else is writing it
out and I'm just pasting it in that
would be ideal and if not like they're
willing to paste a description that's
good to know yeah that's the level of my
I can't write it out figure it out but
yeah so I think that's a good house in
the next week oh well I was able to do
it maybe we want to instead of having me
in the hot seat because I'm good having
um the Facebook group in the hot seat
like how do we remember what I said at
the beginning like can we orchestrate or
were we orchestrating inwards to join
this what what this is what this
Saturday morning project is to type out
so that it can we can post it in
facebook so that there's more people
joining is ideally this wouldn't you
know who'd have 30 people here and gonna
be on zoom and be breaking into groups
and having that be be more powerful and
then yeah let me explain that for people
who aren't on this video so that it's
actually something they want to do yeah
I've gotten mixed up between the
meetings myself I actually don't
remember what the juggling and the
alternating and stuff that can be hard
to be like which one is this what time
is this what version of this time is
this yeah which is I think why like it's
nine am Suffolk Standard Time we get
together we say what our project is if
we add but if we've shown up repeatedly
we made like maybe we don't need to hear
what reason scores every time but it's
also a good practice
like you're welcome to give us this feel
every time but like what you've done
what you are saying you're gonna do and
what you could use help with right and
then everyone else does that same thing
and then we check for one person takes
the hot seat and it gets more focused
help from the group of three to four and
that we're looking to grow it anyone as
long as we know who's gonna show up we
can have up to hundred people when or
near that we're good and then once we
get anywhere close to that where we're
having more then we can open up a second
section second session and maybe some of
us do 2 p.m. and some of us do 9:00 a.m.
right because those two times work for
both the three of us generally so if
some of us are showing up for the 9 a.m.
and some of us are showing up for the 2
p.m. yet anyway but like dad doesn't
associate to be in the first part right
now it's like 9 am 9 am well but we
could mention the will open up more time
slots as this one becomes more popular
we're people that it doesn't work for so
yeah so this is the kind of open
mastermind group for projects above
might be good to explain what a
mastermind is and what we mean by
projects I mean in general I don't know
if we still want to say game B projects
but I think to some date cuz it's like
what you said writing with recent score
you're like this is to game a because
it's a contest because like I feel like
it's too much from a box it's like does
it improve our world little even anyway
great combat you do need help with it
you want to help other people with their
projects like that to me is the bigger
cuz there's people who are game B who
also aren't game be like they don't know
how to create all new in solutions they
haven't dealt with that part of their
ego and they're like we're all gonna
come up with with jealousy strong words
but like conflict of interest and like
oh I don't want like not stepping on my
toes and that's that's part of this
process but if you don't aren't even
aware of that you're just like well no
you can't do that because I'm doing that
I don't know like to me instead of are
you gonna practice a mega rule it's do
you want help on your project and do you
want to help other people on their
project and you
if you sometimes fail at that this is
not our intention
I want your project to succeed I want my
project to succeed that's why we're
having this this hour-long session right
for its can't be all about you but it
also absolutely can be something
somewhat some about you some about you
in your project so like if we did want
to put a link I put a link into the
Wikipedia mastermind group article and
then a link actually happen to know this
guy on the hotseat description but
there's several others I don't know if
that's a great hot seat description of
course I could just say mastermind in
the for Mac and then be flexible we
don't because we made me put the hot
seat format but yeah I just just say
come together to work on our projects to
make improve the world in their place
and we do it you know and it's a
mastermind - maybe the format I'm
wondering if the term round table is a
good sort of like generic description
like if it's the Saturday morning
project round table we're sort of meant
to be like everyone goes around chairs
and then we might end up saying hey you
know we're gonna try the hot seat as
sort of one of the defining features of
this round table but to me that gives a
vibe of light everyone comes everyone
shares everyone gets something out of it
which is it necessarily truism in the
other sessions but this one is meant to
be that yeah we're focusing night
I think that's yeah I'm just wondering
if round table implies more like a news
show round table where you're
pontificating on what's going on but I
guess if it's project focus the project
round table and it's also like round
table also has less of a like mastermind
like we examine Center the minutes
wasn't gonna comments like cuz I haven't
done anything in the last week and I was
like okay so we all allow down time and
a round table makes it sound like you
can drop in and drop out with good and
it also makes it sound less like I need
to have had my together and you
stroke
I did nothing this last week that is
valid and take on something new then the
next one and I we should probably
explicitly say that you don't even have
to have a project to participate because
you can't give feedback and yeah that's
a really good point that's something
that I want to get more of these people
who don't have projects but especially
if you are interested in to me you might
want to help like I want to get inside
that person's head to figure out how do
we get more of you that's that you know
we need like a ten-to-one we way more of
them than actual projects yeah yeah it
is part of that so roundtable also I
think also gives that impression because
it can be I don't have a project I'm
thinking this might be my project or I
have no idea I'm here for like all of it
and I think around table is more you
bring you to the table and whatever
ideas you have in that moment that day
right I'm working having a new zoom call
on orange is the new black okay like I
guess it really matter what it is it's
like this is what I'm working on this
week table I like that more maybe we
implicitly imply drop in drop out this
is about we want more and more
participation but it doesn't need to be
the same people right this isn't right
yes no what happened last time
mastermind usually or are more private
little round tables or more public so
yeah and this one is also more as long
as we're cannot consistently getting six
people I'd say we continue doing it with
this format I mean I'm happy it to any
day let's say that we have our seventh
person show up I'm happy to not be here
right I'd like to just ordered like be
here but facilitate this conversation
and pop people up and down as opposed to
might be the note taker or something
right with green odd but take a stab at
it before that like rotating through
that to showcasing hey then that might
even be its position that someone's like
actually I prefer that to not be on
camera just be taking notes I know
that's not me but because they're like
from my point of view there's no baggage
associated with that term the thing is
that game be and mastermind and worried
that will get mired in the well that's
not mastermind or that's not game be and
then you
as opposed to just do it well hash it
out later maybe we shouldn't have talked
about that or like Oh baby we don't do
that Porsha next session because that
kind of got negative or whatever the
reason is
turns out the eugenics project was not
very kidding me we know for next time
all right
I have a question
um I'm wondering I'm a little confused
with all the different times and videos
and groups so Jubilee you mentioned
before that we could possibly have just
like a session where we're imagining the
world with our projects in it or with
like my project isn't really a specific
project but it's really a platform for
all solution projects this kind of
supports projects widely and shows the
connectivity like our interconnectivity
and how important that is but it's not a
specific project that would support all
of these projects anyway I'm just
curious if there's a specific group or
time or it'd be good to discuss that
kind of thing where it's not one
specific foreplay or thing does that
make sense I think what you're talking
about is maybe the idea cafe for
projects because there's solution
raising which is you know we do we talk
with the possibility of the future but
you don't bring your project to it all
you bring you to it and any knowledge
you have so you kind of bring your
project to it it's my project you know
to me it's like my umbrella project to
do to do solution raising but
theoretically every other Friday we're
having idea cafes on Fridays at noon on
like a question that you can bring your
project so last time it was how could
your project help during the pandemic if
it was ready up and going like right now
not very not a lot but if it if we had
had time to create one and so may be
Shilo you and I could brainstorm more
questions like that that are
more the generative conversation around
what all of our projects existed in the
world right and what what are those that
to put people in the visioning space of
wow not only his reasons for there but
so is wiki election so is his solution
raising so his cube spawn so are all
these things what does the world look
like like that without like focusing too
much on that right where people feel
like they have to have like a degree and
imaginary science or they can just don't
be part of it like just answer the
question that's all you have to do and
you can even pass on the question but
generating a question that is more open
and generative this noon on Fridays work
for you Shilo it's noon pacific standard
time normally I would say yes but you
know everybody is like all freed up now
that this coab is thing is going on but
my partner is a builder and so he's home
and now we have like a million projects
to do at home because he's here it's to
play oh give me just a minute
but I want to say normally yes noon on
Fridays would be good if this Friday
works for you we can set up an idea cafe
for this Friday so we just had two board
meetings in a row cuz we didn't set that
up and like I said I'm taking on putting
up these videos again so if you want to
coordinate after this and say yes we'll
do this Friday as an idea cos a even if
you don't show up for it and it ends up
well I don't know maybe I will if I
schedule it with you like specifically
then I will make sure to make it okay
give you a reason to leave that project
to go do something else
exactly Oh many hit this one at 9 a.m.
will put up a post for a roundtable with
more of that language and then also a
poet will craft a question for the idea
cafe and put that that up as well for
Friday and Saturday next week and I was
just thinking maybe it'd be good to have
a pinned post on the game view projects
page just with the listing and then
descriptions below of what the different
things are yeah wouldn't that be great
at noon this and Friday at nine yeah I
mean the things we could actually put
events in the Facebook page I don't know
that's a pain yeah it's a bit of a pain
it started doing that and then it's both
like you still have to do the posting
and that people see and respond to and
then they respond to that and not this
and it's it's a little but then there is
the beauty of having calendar but I
think that Adrian's current knack
project is the best solution for that
where you have you can be an individual
who can see the calendar for every for
all of this stuff under together attack
and conjoin it or not yeah and you can
also yeah you can see more what's going
on in the broader sense and then also
but I think yes having a pins post that
says this is what an idea cafe is and
when they take place this is with the
board meeting is and when it takes place
this is what the round tables are when
they take place and here are the maybe
it's two different posts but here are
what we can do right we can have a snot
a solution right see that's my project
the other one project raising right like
you can you host one at any time it
doesn't need to be Saturday's that we're
available like anytime you want to post
it if there's enough traffic and
hopefully somebody can be make it and we
can you know you you can be in the hot
seat you can choose to be in the hot
seat and we can focus on your project if
people are available during that that
time slot like this is something that on
your schedule you could do this right on
your schedule you can have an idea cafe
ask a question how people show up but we
also have one scheduled for this this
time period every other Friday are you
saying there is a calendar or not yet
there isn't a calendar there kind of is
under a journal is just kind of working
with knack and figure you know right
there's gonna be a physical calendar
right then I can see what's happening
over the course of a week or over the
course of a month okay that feature
doesn't work great a knack I it does it
but for some reason it doesn't have an
end time so it just assumes all the
events are two hours for and that
doesn't work great
four time zones with just how it's
designed so right now it's just a grid
and there's a column for each I think
I'm tracking three time zones Pacific
Eastern and and UTC but we can add more
and then the idea there is that it's
sort of you can look at the full list or
you can go look at a project and say
tell me what that projects events are
and we can yeah and we can look at doing
a calendar but yeah that's one area
where the calendar at NACA isn't perfect
um we can explore and also anything
that's created in someone else's stuff
isn't gonna be like having like it's an
individual if I want to take if I want
to know what is happening with together
tech and then also what's happening like
I want to be able to choose wiki
lecturers or reasons for like pick the
ones that I want to follow and then see
when there's things alive and I want to
know what their participation is do they
want people live on camera and I would
like or just someone to watch and some
project to participate live or is that
not even necessary I can just watch it
at any point during the week and that's
like one of the things that each event
has a public URL and like it
participates URL so that the public list
always has the public URL but you can't
join unless you're a member and you
signed up for it after playing with it
to figure it out but speaking of which I
came in contact this is one of the
things I would like to do let's just
start a whole new thing and blast by but
it's less of it also something else
they'd like to say but like with under
together tech would talk about like
trading projects from scratch just what
I'm trying to figure out what solution
easy people bringing their projects to
it and and then but you're an ownership
your project together tech doesn't own
it there's no part of the 10,000 people
and $100,000 is finding things that
already meet our needs and buying them
like there are so many team building
apps team building like Monday calm and
task management ones and there was one I
came across this week that looked cool
but the pricing was so astronomical that
I was like who would ever pay this it's
like two hundred fifty dollars a month
or basically like a tree like an idea
tree
that was like hi why would anyone pay
that and but anyway that because all
these things I think are not sustainable
their their success is either to be
bought by Google and Facebook or
basically to go into business or
possibly stay and then but no one stays
in the space right someone buys you and
so if we're the them that buys you that
leg well yours was gonna go to business
anyway a hundred thousand dollars is
better than nothing and then having an
actual but it would need to be something
that meets 90% of our needs that we
would want to have as part of under our
umbrella but like actually that's a
feasible solution like to buy something
that's already there we're like okay
instead of $250 a month for like
ridiculous well how much do you actually
need to make to run this if your options
go out of business or or stay in
business you have a job you have you
know like what do we need so humanity
can use this for free basically not
every new customer pays X amount of
money there's an actual cost anyway to
have the first project we buy if that's
ever an option that maybe take is gonna
be much more complex and much more but
once we start doing that in other
industries then that might be the first
start might be the starting point let's
find out what's in food apps do any of
them work for us can we buy them instead
of right yeah I mean personally that's
kind of my end goal for together tech is
where like it becomes this sort of like
a group owned co-op where it's a co-op
that owns tech like that it's sort of
its yeah and my point was just instead
of it being an end goal it might
actually be our first like it is we have
our first from our project projects
right that we're not letting go up
together to act as an oh man that's not
and that but like as under together tech
having 10,000 people buy an app or you
know putting in 10 bucks or 25 bucks
each for now we own a version that's not
$10 a month right that's not X amount
because now we on Monday comm and we can
use it and we can open it up to the
world so the world can use it no matter
what your your project is and with
something like that like none of the
ones that exist are free for very good
reason they need to make a living they
need to but like it's humanity owns it
it's a completely different but we don't
need to make 10 bucks a month
person 4/4 time but if people are paying
that into it it's way cheaper than what
most of them are charging it's not per
organization so it's like do you agree
in the bigger mission of together tech
and then like starting with something
that would actually meet our needs in a
very real way right that is about
creating a team working through tasks
together and doing and could that be
used for projects but anyway that was
just something up in City myths it's
like oh this is actually more feasible
it could be something we could do what
10,000 people 100,000 once we got 10,000
is partly what exists that we want to
buy and it would be in that realm would
be our first one would be in them team
management project management one thing
I haven't looked though is there also
could be some pretty good open source
ones and then we just need to pay for
hosting and someone would I need to
compensate the person who's keeping it
up and running and stuff like that what
would that even be called hmm like I
know it opens so I can Google open
source but what is I mean I don't like a
TD management / task management right
it's like yeah and I don't think we need
to they'd probably be good to have a
long conversation about what features do
we think we need and then then we can go
and someone can do some time researching
that and I think there's a website that
I think phosphites
let's find out the source software well
they often list alternatives so you can
go in there and I think you can just
type in and or there's the cut so
there's a couple of websites we can say
and you could even just Google
alternative to so if we pick one we like
we might just say alternative to and
then research those alternatives and
that's part of it is that most of the
ones that are way too expensive in my in
my line have a free option right so
finding five or six people who want to
work on the project and having like
we're doing Monday comm for the next two
weeks now we're doing this one now we're
doing this one and seeing what they have
and what is there one that we would like
or is there one can we use these
features what features do they have and
then can we create one with
features would be ideal yeah because
with $100,000 I'm pretty sure we could
pay someone to put together an
open-source one that is that is even
better or there's one out there that
exists that has that meets 90% of our
needs already this been done there isn't
a leg it's just about lying in and
having those people be part of them
transparent open conversation what do
you need your mutant Oh a troll no I
think you saw the phone we can't hear
you we can see you that's me yeah I'm
thinking aren't open source app part of
the creative commons and is there a way
to search that way don't get Creative
Commons licenses when they do open
source apps that are free to anyone well
you can actually have open source
without most of them are some sort of
there's several licenses yeah we would
have to look at the licensing but why I
was thinking I think there's a couple of
sites that are specifically their goal
is to help promote open software so they
kind of our place that people go to I
didn't want to know you would definitely
classify Bentley that was like okay it
turns out that website was wrong so
ignore that that sounds like a cool
option something where I can be like
like Facebook but we own it my favorite
open source
whoa so you can you can do I think
there's alternative to dot something but
if you could you can just search
alternative to and put in the name and
the I can't remember the name of all the
sites but there are some that will come
up and like open source calm is a place
where you like the top line is top seven
open-source project management tools for
agile teams five open source
alternatives to Trello so that would
probably be a good resource to just like
research on I get it I get the
difference between open source and like
Facebook and Google
but somebody needs to make these things
we're like everyone can come to it where
it isn't you don't need to understand
what open source is because like every
team having their own little will take
that and we'll run with it and we can
make this work for us isn't the same as
like I can go and see all of the
projects that I'm part of I can go and
be part of all the Trello boards that I
want right from the open source but
that's just interesting uh it could get
I think we're gonna end this right away
anyway right step out for a second so we
can say goodbye to YouTube thanks for
hanging out we'll see you on Friday